oxfordadvancedlearnersdictionary.com 2016-05-11

# Privacy Policy | Oxford Learner's Dictionaries

Updated on: 19 January 2015

Effective from: 19 January 2015

This privacy policy is specific to www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com (“the Website”) and overrides any other privacy policies appearing elsewhere on Oxford University Press websites or apps.

Oxford University Press ("OUP") is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy explains how we will do this. We will review this privacy policy in the light of comments we receive so please check the latest version. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us by emailing us at [eltsupport@oup.com](mailto:eltsupport@oup.com "link opens a new email").

By using the Website, you are accepting the practices described in this statement.

### WHAT KIND OF INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW DO WE USE IT?

If you are a premium user, your personal information will be used to enable us to verify that you are a premium user and to deliver any restricted content on the Website to you.

We request personal information (such as your name, email address and other contact details) from you when you contact us with queries, technical problems, to comment on the Website, or when you ask for information about how to use the content and/or services made available on the Website. Personal information submitted by you via the contact us page will not be added to our customer databases and we request it simply so that we can respond to you about your query. Statistics regarding the types of queries submitted to us via the contact us page may be collated by us in aggregate form so that we can effectively monitor the Website and improve levels of service.

If you have asked for information or registered for access to restricted content on the Website in the past i.e. procured premium access which is no longer valid, and do not wish us to store information about you, please contact us and we will remove your details from our customer databases. We need to store information about current premium users in order to fulfil our contractual requirements to you and grant you access to restricted content on the Website.

### WHAT KIND OF INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

When you use the Website (e.g. visit, register as a user and/or activate a code entitling you to premium access), we may collect and process the following information about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the Website, procuring an access code or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion on the Website, and when you report a problem with the Website.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, the resources that you access, and the activities which you carried out, any content (whether audio or written) created by you.

### USE OF COOKIES

OUP uses “cookies” and other technologies on the Website. The terms and conditions governing OUP’s use of "cookies" and such other technologies on the Website are set out in OUP’s Cookie Policy.

By using the Website, you are agreeing to be bound by the terms of our [Cookie Policy](http://global.oup.com/cookiepolicy "link opens in a new window").

### HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in the interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.
  * To help us understand more about how the Website is used and to improve the Website.

### WHEN DO WE SHARE INFORMATION?

We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We share your information within OUP. We also share your information with our affiliates, our licensors, our agents, our distributors and our suppliers that assist us in making the Website and/or the products and services on the Website available to you (e.g. our hosting supplier).

If you sign up for services that are managed or offered by other organisations, they will obtain your information.

A number of third party advertisers have links on the Website. If you access any of those third party offerings, such third parties may collect information. Such third party offerings are not within our control and are not covered by this privacy policy. They may have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for those policies. Please check those policies before you submit any personal data to such third party.

If we believe that your use of the Website is unlawful or damaging to others, we reserve the right to disclose the information we have obtained through the Website about you to third parties to the extent that it is reasonably necessary in our opinion to prevent, remedy or take action in relation to such conduct.

We may also disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation; in order to enforce or apply any agreements or licences with you; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of OUP, our employees, affiliates, agents, distributors, licensors, suppliers, and/or our customers. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

If any part of our business (including those of our affiliates) is sold or integrated with another business, your details may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and their advisers.

### SECURITY AND OUR PARTNERS OUTSIDE EUROPE

As a major international publisher, committed to the widest possible dissemination of scholarship and learning, OUP has links with other organisations throughout the world. We exchange information with our overseas branches, associated companies and other parties, including distributors and sales agents. As such, from time to time, we may transfer, store and/or process information about you at a destination outside of the European Economic Area. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. By using the Website, you consent to these transfers.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### UPDATING YOUR DETAILS AND CONTACTING US

If you have any questions or queries regarding this privacy policy, please contact us by sending an e-mail to [eltsupport@oup.com](mailto:eltsupport@oup.com "link opens a new email").

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy. Any changes we may make to this privacy policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### GOVERNING LAW

You agree that this privacy policy shall be exclusively governed in accordance with the laws of England and Wales and subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the court of England and Wales.
